Is this Scotch whisky?
蘇格蘭嗎
Sorry, this is Bourbon whisky.
不好意思 是波本
Are you alright?
你還好嗎
Your id has been taken away for quite a while now.
伊德被人挖走已經過不少時間了
Well, I'm surprisingly holding up.
這個嘛 意外地還撐得下去
Do you mean if I am really okay?
是說 這樣好嗎
I am Noir of Immortal Nine.
我可是不朽九人的諾瓦爾呢
I am your target, aren't I?
是妳的目標不是嗎
You saved me.
你救了我
And Gene didn't ask me to kill you.
而且吉恩沒有下令要處分掉你
I see.
這樣啊
We can't go back.
已經回不了頭了喔
I've made up my mind.
我已經決定了
I want to witness all of this to the end for Noid.
要為了諾伊德 見證這一切直到最後
But Alter and his men will be ready on Venus.
但是奧塔他們 會在金星嚴陣以待吧
Is it okay if we just simply go there like this?
這樣傻傻衝進去沒問題嗎
Who do you think I am?
你以為我是誰啊
How could I go to Venus unarmed to pick a fight?
我怎麼可能手無寸鐵 就去金星找人幹架呢…
I have something to report.
有事稟報
Miss Cyan is missing.
希安小姐不見了
What?
什麼
She disappeared when I wasn't paying attention.
她趁我不注意時消失無蹤
Now she's missing.
現在下落不明
I am truly sorry.
真的非常抱歉
Hey, it will be bad if that grumpy girl starts messing around again.
喂 要是那個像炸彈般的女孩 再來搗亂的話就糟了啊
Where did she run off to?
她到底是跑去哪裡了
She won't run away.
肯定在某個地方吧
Compared to that, look at this.
比起那種事 你們看看這個
As long as we have this,
只要有了這個就是如虎添翼
it's as if Rouge and I join forces.
有如露瓊與我聯手一樣啊
Don't freak out when you see this.
看了可別嚇到喔
This is our ultimate weapon.
這就是我們的最終兵器…
What?
咦
Sister.
姊姊
(Metallic Rouge)
《金屬口紅》
You dropped it?
妳把它丟了
You dropped the anti-phaser to the sea?
把反相位振動器丟到海裡去了
I couldn't hide in with that thing there.
有那東西在我躲不進去啊
What's that thing?
那個反什麼的是什麼東西
That's for analyzing the electromagnetic frequency emitted when Gladiators are in action.
那是分析鬥士在行動時 電磁波所發出的頻率…
And then…
然後…
Simply put,
簡單來說
for the phase reversal from the fight you had earlier,
就是能將打得難分難捨的妳們
this device can do the same thing.
產生相位逆轉之類的東西
Thank you for the explanation.
謝謝你的解說
But you don't have to drop it.
但是也用不著丟掉吧
I didn't know it's important.
我又不知道那是重要物品
Why did you come here?
妳為什麼會來這裡呢
Because I want to be with my sister.
我想要跟姊姊在一起
What?
咦
Has her personality changed?
她的個性是不是不太一樣了啊
What are you scheming?
妳在打什麼算盤
Scheming?
算盤?
You're not supposed to be like this.
妳本來不是這樣的人吧
Didn't you want to kill Rouge?
妳不是想要殺露瓊嗎
I-I didn't want to kill her.
我…沒有想要殺她
I just wanted to play with her.
我只是想要跟姊姊玩而已
What?
什麼
Play with her?
妳那個是玩喔
I heard a voice.
我聽到一個聲音
Get rid of Metal Rouge.
破壞鋼鐵露瓊
Once I hear this voice,
只要聽到這個聲音
I must execute the order.
我就非得去做
Whose voice is it?
是誰的聲音
Is it the voice of the person who created you?
製造妳的人嗎
No.
不是
That's not the voice of the masked father.
不是面具人爸爸的聲音
You were created by Puppetmaster.
妳果然是操偶師所製造出來的
I think she really wants to play with you.
想跟妳玩應該是她 原本心裡所抱持的真正想法吧
Though it's possible that she might hear that voice again…
雖然她再度聽到聲音的可能性 也不是沒有…
Doesn't every Nean hear the voice?
不是每個涅安都會聽到聲音嗎
You've heard it too.
妳也聽到過吧
I haven't.
並沒有
Wait.
等一下
Are you a Nean?
妳是涅安嗎
What?
咦
Don't you know?
你不知道嗎
I don't know.
不知道啦
First likes to keep secrets.
First可是秘密主義者呢
Please don't call me that.
拜託 不要這樣叫我
What does "First" mean?
那個"First"是什麼意思
That's Naomi's real name.
是直美的本名
It is not.
才 不 是 咧
Stay away from Rouge.
快放開露瓊
No way.
我不要
I can't let her go with us.
不能讓載著她跟我們一起去
What should I do?
要怎麼辦才好
Got it.
有了
Deal with her using that cold equation.
用"冷方程式"來處理她吧
Are you going to throw her out into space?
妳要把她丟出去宇宙嗎
You are so cruel.
太殘忍了吧
This kid is a stronger Gladiator than Rouge.
這孩子是個比露瓊還厲害的鬥士
No one can stop her if she loses control.
她要是亂來 沒人能擋得住她的
She's a stronger Gladiator than me?
比我厲害…
In what way?
厲害在哪
She knew immediately that I'm a Nean.
她一下子就發現我是涅安了
And you've been with me so long, but you didn't notice it.
表示有將妳那一直跟我同行
It means your dullness has lessened.
卻完全沒發現 的遲鈍部分給改良了吧
You're really annoying, First.
妳很煩欸 First
Don't call me that.
不要這樣叫我啦
This ship has an escape pod, right?
這艘船沒有逃生艙嗎
Just stuff her in there.
只要把她塞進去就行了
So scary.
好可怕
First, you are really cruel.
First學姐真是殘忍
Who knows when she'll hear that voice again and change back to original state.
誰知道她什麼時候又會聽到聲音 然後變回原樣
There's no need to do so.
那也用不著這樣…
No way.
我不要…
Wait.
咦 妳等一下…
No way!
我絕不要
- She's super rebellious. - No way!
-她超叛逆的欸 -我不要…
- Stop now.
-快停下來啦 -我絕對不要
- You are really being dangerous. - No way!
-這樣真的很危險啦 -我不要…
Let's play.
一起玩吧
Really?
真的嗎
Hmm.
嗯…
That's great.
太棒了
Welcome.
歡迎各位
This way, please.
這邊請
This place has been occupied by us, the Alters.
這裡已被我們奧塔所佔領
We sent those Neans who had been forced into labor
那些被強迫勞動的涅安們
to a safe place.
已讓他們先去安全地區避難了
Do you understand what happens
阿茲莫夫代碼一旦失效 會發生什麼事
when Asimov Code is disabled?
你們明白嗎
Revolution. Slaves will be set free.
革命 解放奴隸
This has happened several times in human history.
這在人類歷史上發生了好幾次
Some things must be achieved by violence.
有些事是必須用激烈手段來達成的
Guys, we have arrived.
各位 我們到了
Thank you all for coming
感謝諸位遠道而來
to attend the feast I host.
前來參與我所舉辦的盛宴
It is a feast for us Neans,
是我們涅安的盛宴
not you.
不是你的
Puppetmaster.
操偶師…
I thought you were an agent of the Usurpers.
我一直認為你是篡奪者的特務
Looks like you're a human.
看起來你似乎是人類
Why do you help them?
你為什麼要協助他們
I'm just an insignificant performer,
我只是個微不足道的演出家
and the Usurpers are my sponsors.
而篡奪者則是我的贊助商
They also want to watch my elaborate stage performance.
我認為他們也想看看 我所精心籌備的舞台表演
We all share the same dream.
我們彼此都抱持著相同的夢想
How about you and the Visitors?
反觀你們與來訪者又是如何呢
Do you share the same mind?
彼此之間的心意是相通的嗎
The meal is ready.
餐點已為各位備妥
Please, this way.
各位 這邊請
This one is my sister, me, and my dad.
這個是姊姊跟我還有爸爸
And this is the home we all live in together.
然後這個是大家一起住的家
My sister and I would go to school from here every day.
姊姊每天都會跟我一起 從這裡出發去上學
Is that me?
那個是我嗎
Your dad is so mysterious.
爸爸也長得太神秘了吧
What does your dad usually do?
爸爸平常是做什麼的呢
Well…
嗯…
He sells pancakes.
是賣鬆餅的
Hilarious.
笑死
This is that kind of comic where you can't judge someone by his look.
這是那種不能從外表判斷職業 的學習漫畫呢
My sister and I would eat my dad's pancakes.
姊姊跟我會吃爸爸做的鬆餅
We sing and dance on holidays.
假日的時候會唱歌跳舞
We play together.
大家玩在一起
It's a horror comic.
原來是恐怖漫畫啊…
Do you like drawing?
妳喜歡畫畫嗎
I can be anything in my drawing.
在畫裡可以成為任何東西
I am free in my drawings.
在畫裡是自由的
Free?
自由…
But it's actually kind of weird that you call her sister.
不過實際上 妳叫她"姊姊"是不是怪怪的啊
What?
咦
Because Rouge was created by Dr. Eva,
因為露瓊是艾娃博士製造的
while you were created by Puppetmaster, right?
希安則是操偶師製造的不是嗎
That's not weird at all.
才不奇怪
My dad also said Rouge is my sister.
爸爸也說了 露瓊姊姊是我的姊姊
Since you were created based on Rouge's data,
既然你是以露瓊的資料 為基礎製造出來的話
you're technically her doppelganger, aren't you?
嚴格來說 應該算是分身吧
She is my sister.
她是我的姊姊
In other words, you are a clone.
換句話說就是複製人
Then she's not really your sister.
那也不是姊姊啊
First, you're a mean old lady who lives nearby.
First是住附近的壞心眼老太婆
Hey!
喂
Oh my.
真是的…
This is…
這裡是…
Do you like it?
你喜歡嗎
You miss it, don't you?
很懷念對吧
I recreated the house we lived in when we were kids.
我重現了我們小時候住的那個家
Are these our ids?
這個…是大家的伊德嗎
Right.
沒錯
After all, a family should stay together, right?
果然一家人 就是要齊聚一堂才好對吧
A family?
一家人
Aren't I a captive?
我不是俘虜嗎
It won't be long before Neans take over the world,
再過不久 涅安就會君臨這個世界
then you will act as the savior of humans
屆時你將會以人類救世主的身分
and lead them
來引導他們
to obey our orders.
對我們唯命是從 百依百順
You are the only one to do it because you're part of our family.
就因為你是我們的家人才能勝任
This is a mission only you can achieve.
這是只有你才能完成的任務
I'm flattered.
妳太抬舉我了
You can do it.
你有這個資格
And you knew it yourself, right?
你自己應該也明白吧
Let's talk about the difficult part later.
艱深的話題晚點再聊吧
By the way, do you remember
對了 你還記得嗎
we have gone to play by the lake?
大家一起去湖邊玩的事情
Giallon said he wanted to drive back then.
當時迦隆還說他想開車呢
That was really terrible.
那次真的很慘
I thought I would die.
我還以為死定了
This guy's been crazy ever since.
這傢伙從那時候起就瘋瘋癲癲的
Thank you for the compliment.
多謝誇獎
Broma chocolate.
布洛碼巧克力
Eva bought this for you on the way to the lake, right?
這是艾娃去湖邊的路上 買給你的對吧
You split it in half, and gave me the bigger half.
你將它分成二半 還把大的那一半給我
From then on, I love to eat this chocolate.
從那個時候開始 我就很愛吃這個巧克力
I don't quite remember.
我不記得了
Do you remember that?
那你記得那個嗎
Gene and I asked Verde to go boating with us at the lake.
我跟吉恩在湖邊找維杜一起去划船
But he didn't want to get on the boat, because his books would get wet.
他卻說"書會濕掉"不想上船
That sounds very much like Verde.
很像是維杜會說的話
He is addicted to reading.
他是個書呆子呢
Achillus is very conscious of the eyes around her and always dressed in fashion.
阿基里斯很自戀 總是花枝招展的
Exactly.
沒錯
She held up her parasol even it's not necessary.
明明不需要 卻還是撐起了陽傘
Nius is very good at swimming.
紐斯很會游泳
He swam around in the water like a dolphin.
在水裡像海豚一樣游來游去
Viola even sang along with his swimming strokes.
拜歐拉還隨著他的泳姿歌唱
A holiday spent together with family.
一家人一起度過的假日
The best memory ever.
最棒的回憶…
It would be nice if Eden were also here.
要是伊甸也在這裡就好了
Is Eden still alive?
伊甸他還活著嗎
His id has been pulled out,
他的伊德已經被拔了出來
so he might be dead by the roadside a long time ago.
可能已經死在路邊了吧
Well, it's hard to say.
這個嘛 可不好說喔
Giallon.
迦隆
Thanks to you, my love, for showing mercy at the end,
多虧心愛的妳在最後留了一手
so I can survive.
才能勉強留著一口氣呢
Stop.
別說了
But still,
不過…
the wonderful family memory will fade away.
那美妙的家庭回憶也將漸漸消散
All the memories will be gone
腦裡的一切記憶消失地一乾二淨
and come to an end.
然後走向終結
I told you to stop.
我叫你別說了
I'm sorry.
不好意思
Thank you
謝謝你喔
for bringing up such wonderful old stories.
帶來這美妙的爛陳年往事
Go.
給我去
No way.
我不要
Hurry up.
快給我去
No way!
我 不 要 去
To take a bath.
我叫妳去洗澡啦
You haven't taken a bath in days.
妳已經幾天沒洗了啊
Rouge hasn't either.
露瓊姊姊也沒洗啊
I took a bath this morning.
我早上洗過了
Naomi forced me to.
被直美強押去洗的
What?
咦
You're the only one who hasn't taken a bath.
只剩下妳了喔
It won't kill me.
不洗澡又不會死
It will.
會好不好
If some weird virus starts spreading around here,
要是出現奇怪的病毒 蔓延開來的話
that old man will die.
那個叔叔會死掉喔
Me?
我嗎
Humans will die from diseases.
人類是會因為疾病而死去的
Do you understand?
妳懂嗎
I'm busy right now. I'll go later.
我現在在忙 等一下再去
As a deity officer, I request you to take a bath.
我要以神祇官權限執行強制入浴
No way.
我不要啦
- Stop! - No way.
-給我站住 -我不要
Rouge, catch her.
露瓊 快抓住她
- What? - Sister, save me!
-咦 -姊姊 救救我啦
I remember now.
啊 我想起來了
I saw some ice cream in the pantry.
我有在糧食庫裡看到有冰淇淋呢
What?
咦…
That must be delicious.
那肯定很好吃吧
It'd be nice to have a cool ice cream after taking a bath.
洗完澡後渾身清爽 來一口冰涼的冰淇淋一定超讚
What flavor is it?
是什麼口味
It's of vanilla and chocolate.
香草和巧克力的雙重口味
I'll go take a bath.
我去洗澡
You know how to handle a kid.
你挺會應付小孩的嘛
After all, I am a father too.
畢竟我也是身為人父的人嘛
Do you have a kid?
你有小孩啊
I haven't seen my kid since my divorce.
離婚後就沒再見面就是了
Seeing Noid
看著諾伊德
reminds me of my son,
彷彿會讓我想起我的兒子
so I didn't get too close to him.
所以我才盡量不對他投入太多心力
I think I should have talked to him more.
現在想想 我應該要多跟他聊聊的
Even in my free time outside of work, I should have spent more time with him.
就連工作以外的空閒時間 也該多跟他相處的
The things that we truly value
心裡真正重視的事物
are always found to be important after we lose them.
總是在失去之後才發現啊
Maybe so.
或許真是如此喔
I also have things I value.
我也有重視的事物…
It's my important family.
那些家人
Do you mean the Immortal Nine?
你是指不朽九人嗎
Immortal…
不朽…
Yes.
啊…是啊
They are as important as my family.
他們也像是我家人一般重要
But,
但是…
there are more important things than them.
還有比這些更重要的存在…
A lover?
情人嗎
Really?
真的假的
Is it a Nean?
對方是涅安嗎
It's just the person I love.
所愛之人
That's all.
僅止於此罷了
If you think of them as your family,
如果你把他們當成是家人
then why are you still on our side?
那為什麼還要站在我們這邊呢
Because I regret it,
算是後悔吧
just like you.
跟你一樣
Fulfilling the dreams of the one I love
實現所愛之人的夢想
is the least I can do.
這是我所能做出的小小彌補
(Episode 10: Family Portrait)
(10 家人的肖像)
Can't you sleep?
睡不著嗎
Yes.
是啊…
Everyone has family, valuable things or a cherished memory with someone.
大家都有家人 重視之物 或是跟某人的珍貴回憶呢
Memories aren't all good.
回憶也不一定全是好事
That's true.
是這麼說沒錯
The fact that they have something I could never have
只是看到他們有著 自己絕對無法擁有的東西
makes me feel a bit jealous.
不免讓我覺得有些羨慕
Seriously, I'm on vacation.
真是的 人家在休假欸
If we go head-on, we'll get shot down and die.
要是直行 我們會被擊落 直接玩完
Even if we're lucky enough to land on Venus,
就算運氣好 成功降落金星
the real problem would start then.
那接下來才會是問題
Sister.
姊姊
Let's play.
來玩吧
Cyan.
希安
I am discussing something important with Rouge.
我在跟露瓊說重要的事
Don't disturb us.
不要來搗亂
It's you who's disturbing.
是直美妳在搗亂吧
I want to play with my sister. Don't disturb us.
我要跟姊姊玩 妳不要來搗亂
If you hadn't dropped the anti-phaser,
要不是你把反相位振動器丟掉
we don't have to work so hard, get it?
我們也不用這麼辛苦 妳懂嗎
Alright.
好了啦
What do you want to play?
要玩什麼呢
Is that okay?
可以嗎
We'll just go in there and make a scene.
我們就直接衝進去 大鬧一番
Just like we always do.
像平常那樣做吧
Everything will be okay.
一切都會沒問題的
Rouge, are you truly prepared?
露瓊 妳真的有做好覺悟嗎
This battle is different from the past one.
這次的戰鬥跟過去不同
We must not fail.
絕對不許失敗
You want to save Gene, right?
妳不是想要救回吉恩嗎
Isn't that why we're going to Venus?
不是為此才要去金星的嗎
No.
不對
More than this.
不只是這樣
I'm going to stop Silvia and her men
希爾維雅他們想做的事
from doing what they're trying to do.
我也要一併阻止
I will protect the freedom of humans and Neans.
我要守護人類與涅安的自由
I shall fulfill the wishes of the one I love.
所愛之人的心願 由我來實現
You are truly prepared.
妳的覺悟很堅定嘛
Then now is not the time to play.
那現在就不是玩的時候了吧
Who is Gene?
"吉恩"是誰
That's Rouge's real family,
是露瓊"真正的"家人
her real brother.
是她"真正的"哥哥
What?
咦
If he's the real brother of Rouge,
如果說他是露瓊姊姊 真正的哥哥的話…
then wouldn't that make him my brother too?
那不就是我哥哥嗎
Alright.
好了…
You go play by yourself.
妳一個人去旁邊玩
I hate you.
我討厭妳
What?
咦
I hate Naomi.
我討厭直美
I really hate Naomi.
我最討厭直美了
No way.
不可以
Naomi.
直美…
It hurts.
好痛…
I must…
我一定要…
I must let her suffer the cold equation.
對她處以"冷方程式"之刑
Did you do so
妳剛剛的舉動
because you heard someone's voice?
是因為聽到誰的聲音嗎
No.
沒有
If so, it's your fault.
如果是這樣 那就是妳的錯喔
You can't hurt her just because you don't like her.
不能因為不喜歡 就肆意去傷害對方
Hmm.
嗯
And even if you do hear someone's voice,
而且就算妳真的聽到誰的聲音
you can choose not to listen to it
妳也可以選擇要不要聽從它
and make your own decisions.
妳可以自己做出決定的
Make my own decisions?
自己…
Exactly.
沒錯
Can you do it?
妳可以嗎
I'll try.
嗯 我試試看
Okay.
好
I want to be your real younger sister.
我也要成為姊姊真正的妹妹
Okay?
可以嗎
Just like what Gene did for me.
就像吉恩為我做的那樣
I want to be your real elder sister.
我也要成為妳真正的姊姊
Hmm.
嗯
What about Naomi?
直美呢
What?
咦
What is Naomi to you?
直美是姊姊的什麼人呢
Naomi and you seem to be very close,
我看直美跟姊姊好像很要好的樣子
so I feel a bit jealous.
覺得有點羨慕
Naomi?
直美?
Naomi…
直美啊…
Well…
嗯…
What is Naomi to you?
直美對姊姊來說 是什麼樣的存在呢
She's my best friend?
最棒的外人吧
What does it mean?
那是什麼意思
Well,
這個嘛…
sometimes she can be very irritating,
她有時候很讓人火大
but I can stay with her.
但可以一直跟她待在一起
Naomi is my best friend.
直美是最棒的外人了
What's wrong?
怎麼了
I don't know.
這是為什麼呢
I forgot how to hum the rest of it.
我忘記後面要怎麼哼了
Then start again.
那再重新哼一次吧
I don't remember.
我想不起來…
I still remember
我還記得
the time when we went for a row on the lake.
跟你一起在湖上划船的事
It was a very happy holiday.
是個很開心的假日
At that time,
那個時候
you looked about my age.
吉恩看起來跟我差不多大
I was so happy because I felt like I've made a friend.
我感覺像是交到了個朋友 開心得不得了
Me too.
我也是
I can't believe you're part of this operation.
沒想到你居然也參與了這個行動
I am against it.
我是反對的
It's that mindless loser Aes, who's part of this.
參與的是那個腦袋停止思考的 金魚腦廢物艾斯
I can't stop him.
這是沒辦法的事啊
We have to do it, so the Proto-Neans can survive.
這是為了讓原形涅安能活下去啊
To survive?
"為了能活下去"
Are you trying to disgust me?
你是想噁心死我嗎
If we didn't share the same body, I would have killed you myself.
要不是我們共用一個身體 我早就親手殺你了
Aes.
艾斯
Do you think this will be a good memory someday?
你認為這件事 終有一天會成為美好回憶嗎
This is…
這是…
Fate will bring the soul to the most appropriate place.,
命運會將靈魂帶至最為合適之地
becoming the key to unlocking the gate to the future.
成為開啟未來之門的鑰匙吧
In the end,
究竟
will they finally be free?
他們最後得到的會是自由嗎
Or…
又或者是…
Is he extracting data from id?
他是在從伊德裡抽出資料嗎
The last guests have arrived.
最後的客人到了
Rouge.
露瓊
Now,
現在
our final performance is about to begin.
我們最後的表演即將開始
Ladies and gentlemen,
各位觀眾
please enjoy the show to the very end.
還請盡情享受這場演出直到最後
A large number of unidentified flying objects are approaching directly ahead.
前方12點鐘方向 有大量未確認飛行物體接近
Distance is 17000.
距離17000
The ship has been targeted.
本體已被鎖定
Distance remains…
距離接觸還剩…